Hello English learners, welcome back to another great lesson with EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another great lesson about being at the bank.
今天我们要带给大家另一堂关于在银行的精彩课程。
That's right.
没错。
We've got an intermediate lesson for you today with lots of great language to help you open
今天我们为大家准备了一堂中级课程，里面有很多很棒的语言表达，可以帮助你开立
a bank account.
银行账户。
Okay, so let's look at our vocabulary preview today.
好的，那么我们先来看今天的词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Two words today.
今天有两个词。
The first one is checking account.
第一个是支票账户。
A checking account.
支票账户。
Checking account.
So what is a checking account?
那么什么是支票账户呢？
Well, it's a type of bank account that lets you do your day-to-day or daily banking.
嗯，这是一种银行账户，让你可以进行日常银行业务。
So it's the normal bank account that you use to go shopping, that you use to pay your bills.
所以就是你平时购物、付账单用的普通银行账户。
Yep, exactly.
是的，没错。
The opposite, and our second word is...
相反地，我们的第二个词是……
Savings account.
储蓄账户。
A savings account.
Savings account.
储蓄账户。
So a savings account is to...
那么储蓄账户是用来……
It's a bank account where you save your money.
这是一种你存钱的银行账户。
To save money, right?
用来存钱，对吧？
So usually you don't touch the money in this account.
所以通常你不会动用这个账户里的钱。
Yeah, usually it stays in there.
是的，通常钱就放在里面。
Right.
对。
So usually banks will have these two types of accounts.
所以通常银行会有这两种账户。
Yes.
是的。
Checking and savings.
支票账户和储蓄账户。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
Let's listen to our dialogue a first time now.
现在让我们第一次听一下对话。
Right.
好的。
Well, today we're at a bank and we're going to listen as a man is opening a bank account.
今天我们在银行，会听到一位男士正在开立银行账户。
The dialogue is going to be spoken at a normal speed, so it might be a little bit fast.
对话会以正常语速进行，所以可能会有点快。
Yeah.
是的。
But don't worry about it because we'll come back and explain everything.
但别担心，因为我们之后会回来解释所有内容。
Next, please.
下一位。
May I help you, sir?
先生，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Hello.
你好。
Yes, I'd like to open a bank account.
是的，我想开一个银行账户。
Certainly.
当然可以。
I can help you with that.
我可以帮您办理。
What type of account would you like to open?
您想开哪种类型的账户？
A checking or a saving account?
支票账户还是储蓄账户？
What features do they offer?
它们都有什么功能？
Well, if you just take a look here, see, with our checking account, you can have unlimited
嗯，您看一下这里，我们的支票账户每月只需支付少量费用，就可以进行无限次日常交易。
daily transactions for a small monthly fee, and our savings account has a higher interest
而储蓄账户利率更高，但您必须保持至少一万美元的最低余额。
rate, but you must carry a minimum balance of $10,000.
但您必须保持至少一万美元的最低余额。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, I think I'm more interested in a checking account.
嗯，我想我对支票账户更感兴趣。
I'd like to have easy access to my money.
我希望能够方便地取用我的钱。
All right, then.
好的，那么。
With this checking account, you'll be issued a debit card and a checkbook.
使用这个支票账户，我们会给您一张借记卡和一本支票簿。
Will you require overdraft protection?
您需要透支保护吗？
There is an extra fee for that.
那需要额外收费。
No, that won't be necessary.
不，不需要。
In that case, I'll get you to fill out this paperwork.
这样的话，我请您填写这些表格。
I'll need your social insurance number and two pieces of government ID.
我需要您的社会保险号和两份政府签发的身份证件。
If you could just sign here, and here, and here, we'll be all set.
您只需在这里、这里和这里签名，就办好了。
Would you like to make a deposit today?
您今天要存款吗？
Yes, I'd like to deposit $1 billion.
是的，我想存十亿美元。
$1 billion!
十亿美元！
All right, $1 billion.
好的，十亿美元。
That's a lot of money.
那可真是一大笔钱。
That's a weird laugh.
这笑声真奇怪。
Okay, let's look at language takeaway today.
好了，我们来看看今天的语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Today we've got four words for you in language takeaway, all about money and banking.
今天的语言要点，我们为您准备了四个单词，都与金钱和银行业务有关。
Money and banking.
金钱和银行业务。
The first one that we have today is transaction.
今天第一个词是“交易”。
Transaction.
交易。
A transaction.
一笔交易。
So we have some great examples that will help you understand what a transaction is, so let's
我们有一些很好的例子，可以帮助您理解什么是交易，让我们来听听。
listen.
听。
Example one.
例子一。
I need a record of my most recent bank transactions.
我需要一份我最近的银行交易记录。
Example two.
例子二。
There is no fee for bank transactions done online.
网上银行交易不收取任何费用。
Example three.
例子三。
Okay, we've deposited your money.
好的，我们已经存入了您的钱。
Would you like to make another transaction today?
您今天还想进行其他交易吗？
So basically I can understand that a transaction is moving money around in your bank account.
所以基本上我可以理解，交易就是在银行账户之间转移资金。
Right, it's taking your money from your bank account and putting it in another account
对，就是把钱从你的银行账户取出来，放到另一个账户里，
or just taking it to spend, whatever.
或者只是取出来花掉，等等。
Yes.
是的。
That's a transaction.
那就是一笔交易。
Or even putting money into your bank account.
甚至把钱存入银行账户。
That's also a transaction.
那也是一笔交易。
Great.
太好了。
Our second word, balance.
我们的第二个词，余额。
Balance.
余额。
So your account balance is how much money you have.
所以你的账户余额就是你有多少钱。
Exactly.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
An account balance.
账户余额。
My account balance is $2 right now, I think.
我的账户余额现在大概是两美元。
That's a bit of a problem.
这有点问题。
Yes.
是的。
Good thing payday is three days away.
还好发薪日还有三天。
Yeah, oh my God.
是啊，天哪。
Okay, our third word, overdraft.
好的，我们的第三个词，透支。
Overdraft.
透支。
So, this really comes in handy, right?
所以，这真的很有用，对吧？
To overdraft, can you tell us a little bit about it?
关于透支，你能给我们讲讲吗？
Let's say in my bank account, I have $500, but I spend $600.
假设我的银行账户里有500美元，但我花了600美元。
Right.
对。
So, I have an overdraft in my account, meaning I owe the bank $100.
那么我的账户就透支了，意思是我欠银行100美元。
Right.
对。
It's also commonly referred to as a negative balance.
这也常被称为负余额。
That's right.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
Negative balance.
负余额。
Like me.
就像我一样。
Very soon, I will have a negative balance.
很快，我的余额就会变成负数了。
Okay, I think this one is a little bit tricky to understand.
好的，我觉得这个词有点难理解。
So let's listen to a couple of examples of how we use this word.
所以让我们听几个例子，看看这个词怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
The maximum overdraft on my account is only $5,000.
我账户的最高透支额度只有5000美元。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm sorry, sir, but you've exceeded your maximum overdraft limit.
对不起，先生，您已经超过了最高透支限额。
I cannot give you any more money.
我不能再给您钱了。
Example three.
例子三。
Oh no, I have to pay $1,500 in overdraft fees.
哦不，我得支付1500美元的透支费。
Okay, great examples.
好的，很好的例子。
Now we can take a look at our last word, debit card.
现在我们可以看看最后一个词，借记卡。
Debit card.
借记卡。
D-E-B-I-T, card.
D-E-B-I-T，卡。
Debit card.
借记卡。
So, a debit card is issued by the bank.
借记卡是由银行发行的。
Yes.
是的。
And used to...
用来……
To get money out of an ATM.
从自动取款机取钱。
From an ATM machine, right?
从自动取款机，对吧？
Right.
对。
A debit card.
借记卡。
Not to be confused with a credit card.
不要和信用卡混淆。
Not the same thing.
不是一回事。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So, now we could listen to our dialogue a second time at a slower speed.
现在我们可以用慢速再听一遍对话。
So now we can...
现在我们可以……
We can hear all of the great language you just talked about.
我们可以听到你刚才讲的所有精彩语言。
Next please.
请继续。
May I help you, sir?
先生，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Hello.
你好。
Yes, I'd like to open a bank account.
是的，我想开一个银行账户。
Certainly.
当然可以。
I can help you with that.
我可以帮您办理。
What type of account would you like to open?
您想开哪种账户？
A checking or a savings account?
支票账户还是储蓄账户？
What features do they offer?
它们有什么功能？
Well, if you just look here...
嗯，如果您看这里……
See, with our checking account, you can have unlimited daily transactions for a small monthly
看，我们的支票账户每月只需支付少量费用，就可以无限次日常交易。
fee.
费用。
And our savings account has a higher interest rate.
而且我们的储蓄账户利率更高。
But you must carry a minimum balance of $10,000.
但您必须保持最低一万美元的余额。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, I think I'm more interested in a checking account.
嗯，我想我对支票账户更感兴趣。
I like to have easy access to my money.
我喜欢方便取用我的钱。
All right then.
那好吧。
With this checking account, you'll be issued with a debit card and a checkbook.
使用这个支票账户，您会收到一张借记卡和一本支票簿。
Will you require overdraft protection?
您需要透支保护吗？
There is an extra fee for that.
那需要额外收费。
No, that won't be necessary.
不，不需要。
In that case, I'll get you to fill out this paperwork.
那样的话，我请您填写这些文件。
I'll need your social insurance number and two pieces of government ID.
我需要您的社会保险号和两份政府身份证件。
If you could just sign here and here and here, we'll be all set.
如果您能在这里、这里和这里签名，就都办好了。
Would you like to make a deposit today?
您今天要存款吗？
Yes, I'd like to deposit $1 billion.
是的，我想存十亿美元。
We heard some interesting phrases of how to tell somebody to do something in a polite
我们听到了一些有趣的表达，关于如何礼貌地告诉别人做某事。
way.
方式。
Yes.
是的。
Let's start with Fluency Builder and explain these words.
我们先从流利度构建开始，解释这些词语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
The bank teller asked this man to do a number of things in order to open his bank account
银行出纳员请这位先生做了一些事情来开立银行账户。
and she used some great expressions.
她使用了一些很好的表达。
Right.
对。
Let's listen to how she asked the man to do some things in a polite way.
我们来听听她是如何礼貌地请这位先生做事的。
Yes.
是的。
I'll get you to fill out this paperwork.
我请您填写这些文件。
I'll need your social insurance number.
我需要您的社会保险号。
If you could just sign here.
如果您能在这里签名。
The first thing she said is, I'll get you to fill out this paperwork.
她说的第一句话是：我请您填写这些文件。
I'll get you to.
我请您。
Right.
对。
I'll get you to.
我请您。
It's just a way of saying, can you please fill this out?
这只是一种说法，意思是：请您填一下这个好吗？
Yes.
是的。
I'll do this, but in a different way.
我会这样做，但用不同的方式。
More polite.
更礼貌。
It's pretty polite.
这相当礼貌。
Then she also said, I'll need your social insurance number.
然后她还说，我需要你的社会保险号。
I'll need your.
我需要你的。
Again, a polite way of saying.
同样，这是一种礼貌的说法。
Give me your social insurance number.
把你的社会保险号给我。
Give me your social insurance.
And the last thing she said, and this is really polite.
她说的最后一件事，这真的很礼貌。
If you could just sign here.
如果你能在这里签字就好了。
Yes.
是的。
If you could just sign here.
请在这里签字。
If you could just.
请稍等。
If you could just wait a moment, I'll be with you.
请稍等一下，我马上就来。
If you could just send me an email with your bank account number.
请把你的银行账号发邮件给我。
Right.
好的。
Very polite way of asking for something.
非常礼貌的请求方式。
Yep.
是的。
Well, some great language in today's cast.
嗯，今天的节目中有一些很棒的语言。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll catch all of this wonderful language.
让我们最后再听一遍对话，把所有这些精彩的语言都掌握。
Next please.
下一位。
May I help you, sir?
先生，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Hello.
你好。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
I'd like to open a bank account.
我想开一个银行账户。
Certainly.
当然可以。
I can help you with that.
我可以帮您办理。
What type of account would you like to open?
您想开哪种类型的账户？
A checking or a saving account?
支票账户还是储蓄账户？
What features do they offer?
它们都有什么功能？
Well, if you just take a look here, see, with our checking account, you can have unlimited
嗯，您看一下这里，我们的支票账户可以无限次
daily transactions for a small monthly fee.
每月只需支付少量费用即可进行日常交易。
And our savings account has a higher interest rate, but you must carry a minimum balance
我们的储蓄账户利率更高，但您必须保持最低余额
of $10,000.
1万美元。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, I think I'm more interested in a checking account.
嗯，我想我对支票账户更感兴趣。
I'd like to have easy access to my money.
我希望能够方便地取用我的钱。
All right, then.
那好吧。
With this checking account, you'll be issued a debit card and a checkbook.
使用这个支票账户，您将获得一张借记卡和一本支票簿。
Will you require overdraft protection?
您需要透支保护吗？
There is an extra fee for that.
那需要额外收费。
No, that won't be necessary.
不，那就不必了。
In that case, I'll get you to fill out this paperwork.
这样的话，我请您填一下这份文件。
I'll need your social insurance number and two pieces of government ID.
我需要您的社会保险号和两份政府签发的身份证件。
If you could just sign here and here and here, we'll be all set.
您只要在这里、这里和这里签名，就可以了。
Would you like to make a deposit today?
您今天要存款吗？
Yes, I'd like to deposit $1 billion.
是的，我想存10亿美元。
$1 billion!
10亿美元！
Okay, so an interesting thing here, not many countries use checks.
好的，这里有个有趣的现象，很多国家都不常用支票。
That's right.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
The checkbook or a check?
支票簿还是支票？
Yeah, it tends to be more of an American thing, don't you think?
是啊，这更像是美国人的习惯，你不觉得吗？
It is, it is.
是的，是的。
I think it is.
我也这么觉得。
For those of you who aren't sure what a check is, it's basically a piece of paper that you
对于那些不太清楚支票是什么的人，它基本上就是一张纸，你
just sign your name and...
只要签上名字，然后……
Yeah, you write the amount of money and then you sign your name, right?
对，你写上金额，然后签上名字，对吧？
Right, and then you give that to the person, that person can take it to the bank and get
对，然后你把支票给对方，对方可以拿去银行，
money in exchange for it.
兑换成现金。
Yes.
是的。
It's not very common in other countries.
这在其他国家不太常见。
No, but from what I know, every single American has a checkbook and uses it pretty regularly.
不常见，但据我所知，每个美国人都有支票簿，而且经常使用。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
For example, you pay your phone bill or your electric bill, you just put a check in the
比如，你付电话费或电费，只要把支票放进
mailbox and it's paid.
邮箱里，就付清了。
And it's done.
就搞定了。
It's an interesting thing.
这挺有意思的。
But also, sometimes in other countries, people's salaries are paid through checks.
不过，有时候在其他国家，人们的工资也是通过支票支付的。
Yes.
是的。
Paycheck.
工资支票。
Oh, yes.
哦，对。
I see where that word comes from.
我明白这个词的由来了。
Paycheck.
工资支票。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
But for example, here in China, it's not very common, right?
但比如在中国，这就不太常见，对吧？
I've never seen a check here.
我在这里从没见过支票。
Me neither.
我也没见过。
What about in your countries?
那你们国家呢？
We'd like to know how the banking system works.
我们想知道银行系统是怎么运作的。
Yes, come to our website at EnglishPod.com and tell us all about it.
是的，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们你的情况。
Yes, and you can also leave your questions and comments on our website and we'll be there
是的，你也可以在我们的网站上留下问题和评论，我们会在那里
to answer it.
回答它们。
Yeah, Marco and I love answering your questions, so please visit us.
是的，马可和我很喜欢回答你们的问题，所以请访问我们。
All right, but until then, it's goodbye.
好了，那么在此之前，再见。
Bye.
再见。